자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
엄마 배고파 죽겠어요
Mom, I'm starving.
곧 피자가 올 거야
The pizza's gonna be here in a minute.
다시 전화해서
독촉해 봐야 하지 않아요?
Maybe, maybe we
should call him again.
똑바르지 않잖아요
It's not straight.
방울이 딱 중간에 있는데요?
The bubble's right in the middle.
평형수준기가 고장 난 거죠
The level's broken.
고장 안 났어요, 몽크 씨
The level is not broken, Mr. Monk.
이런 게 어떻게 고장 나요
막대기에 공기방울 하나 있는 건데
It can't be broken.
It's a bubble on a stick.
수준기가 또 있었어요?
You have two levels?
다른 수준기가 맞는지 보려고
이걸 사용하죠
I use this level
to check the other levels.
수준기 확인용 수준기예요
It's my level-checking level.
그게 고장 나지 않았는지는
어떻게 알아요?
How do you know that
one's not broken?
좋은 질문이야
That's a good question.
내 수준기 확인용 수준기는 1년에
두 번씩 상점에 가져가 재조정하거든
I take my level-checking level
to the hardware store twice a year
to have it recalibrated.
- 안 오나 싶었네요
- 죄송합니다, 오늘 밤은 바빠서요
- Hey, we were getting worried.
- Sorry. It's a busy night.
12달러 50센트입니다
That's $12.50.
여기 있어요
All right, there you go.
- 고맙습니다
- 고마워요
Thank you. / Thank you.
자, 왔다
All right.
와서 가져가렴
Come and get it.
먹다 흘리지 마라
여기가 어딘지 잘 알지?
Don't make a mess.
Remember where we are.
다 식었잖아요
이럴 줄 알았어
It's cold.
I knew it.
잘 모르겠네요
I can't be sure.
측정기 하나가 더 필요할 거 같네요
We might need another level.
아, 이런, 거스름돈을 잘못 줬잖아
50달러를 줬어요!
Oh, my gosh, he gave me the wrong
change. He gave me a 50!
- 잘 됐네요
- 얘야, 잘된 게 아니야
- Cool.
- No, honey, honey, not cool.
그 사람 사비에서 나온 돈이고
큰돈이잖니
This is gonna come out of his pocket.
This is a lot of money.
금방 갔다 올게
I'll be right back.
- 정말 모르겠는데
- 저도요
I don't know. / No.
기다려요, 기다리세요!
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
보세요! 저기...
Hello!
Excuse...
이봐요
Hi.
이봐요?
Hello?
잠깐만요
Excuse me.
여기요, 거스름돈을
잘못 계산하셨더군요
Here, you gave me the wrong change.
거스름돈을 잘못 ...
Here, you gave me the wrong...
MONK Season 4 Epi. 3
Mr. Monk Stays in Bed
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
한상희(fithelestre@sanori.net)
번역수정
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
한글교정
이미란(lmr0412@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2005/07/22
나탈리, 이리 오세요
Hey, come on.
마실 거라도 좀 가져다 드려요?
- 몽크, 침대에 머물다 -
Can I, uh, can I get you anything?
아뇨
No.
그럼 잠깐 몇 가지만 여쭤 보죠
Okay, this'll just take a minute.
- 수상한 걸 보진 못하셨나요?
- 전혀요
- Uh, so, you didn't see anything?
- No.
들으신 것도 없습니까? 도와달라는
비명이나 외침 같은 거요
Did you hear anything? I mean,
anybody yelling or screaming for help?
제가 비명 지른 건 들렸죠
Yeah, me.
경위님은 아무 느낌도 없으세요?
Does it ever get to you?
죽은 사람을 봤는데도요
Seeing people dead?
한동안은 어쩔 줄 몰랐지요
Yeah, it did for a while.
하지만, 익숙해졌습니다
But I got used to it.
정말 끔찍하겠어요
That must be awful.
이런 일에 익숙해지다니요
Getting used to it.
말씀대로 상당히 끔찍합니다만
You know, it was pretty awful.
그렇게 됐습니다
But I got used to it.
제일 못 해먹을 부분이죠
It's the worst part, you know.
이런 일에 익숙해지는 거요
Getting used to it.
나탈리는 절대 이런 일에
익숙해지진 않겠지요
Something you never really get used to.
이름은 훌리오 알바레즈, 25살이고
His name was Julio Alvarez.
25 years old.
파이프나 원통 모양의
둔기에 맞아 사망했네
He was bludgeoned to death
with a pipe or cylinder.
야구 배트일지도 모르지
Maybe a baseball bat.
흉기가 뭐든 간에
살인자가 갖고 가 버렸네
Whatever it was, the killer
took it with him.
피해자는 어디로 가고 있었죠?
Where was he headed?
빈튼 가에 배달할 게 하나 있었지
He had one more delivery
on Vinton street.
살인범이 어떻게
이 사람 차를 멈춰 세웠을까요?
How did the killer get him to stop?
여기엔 주택은커녕 가게도 없는데요
There are no houses here.
No store fronts here.
나도 그게 궁금했다네
Yeah, I was wondering the same thing.
손을 흔들어 세웠으려나?
Uh, maybe he waved him down?
차 안에 숨어 있었을지도 모르지
Or maybe he hid out in the vehicle.
기억나나? 비슷한 수법이 있었지
Like, uh, do you remember
there was that, um,
멘도 시 지역에서 일어난
차량 강탈 사건에서...
the carjacking in Mendo ci...
뭔가?
What?
왜 그래?
물티슈!
Wipe.
물티슈, 물티슈 줘요!
Wipe, wipe!
- 이런, 다 떨어졌어
- 물티슈...
- Gee, I'm fresh out.
- Wipe...
몽크, 난 물티슈 없네
난 자네 조수가 아니라고
Monk, I don't have a wipe.
I don't work for you.
이를 어쩌나
감기 걸렸나 봐요
Oh, god. I'm getting a cold.
재채기 한 번 갖고 뭘 그래
It was one sneeze.
That's nothing.
아니, 아니에요!
진짜 감기예요
No, no, no, no.
It's a cold.
감기예요, 느낌이 온다니까요
I can feel it.
- 당황하지 마
- 당황 안 해요
- Well, don't panic.
- I'm, I'm not panicking.
구급차 어디 있어요?
Where's the ambulance?
이런
Oh, yeah.
이런 이런, 퍼지고 있어요
It's spreading.
퍼지고 있다고요
드디어 왔어요
It's spreading. Here it comes.
느낌이 와요, 느낌이...
느낌이 와요!
I can feel it, I can feel...
I can feel it.
거참 자네가 아플 일이라곤
절대 없을 줄 알았는데
Whoa, I did not think it was
possible for you to get sick.
아주 용감한 미생물 아닌가
Well, that's one plucky little microbe.
세균으로서는 자네에게 침입하는 건
에베레스트 등반처럼 어려운 일이라고
Yeah, for a germ, you gotta be,
like, climbing mount Everest.
그만 하세요, 안 웃겨요
That's not funny.
이런, 이게 누구시람
부국장님 아니십니까
Hey, look who's here,
deputy commissioner.
무슨 일인가, 반장?
What's the matter, captain?
- 너무 바빠서 전화받을 짬도 없었나?
- 에, 사실은 그랬답니다
- Too busy to answer your phone?
- Well, as a matter of fact, I am.
저희가 살인 사건 수사라고
부르는 상황이 생겼거든요
This is what we call
a homicide investigation.
중대한 사건이 막 생겼네
Well, something important just came up.
상급 법원 판사 한 분이 실종됐어
A superior court judge is missing.
6시 반까지 모금 행사에
나오시기로 했는데
She was supposed to be
at a fundraiser at 6:30.
나타나지 않으셨다네
She never showed up.
6시 반이요? 2시간 지났잖습니까
마빈 부국장님
6:30?
That's two hours, Marvin.
그런 건 실종이 아니라
저녁 식사에 지각했다고 말하죠
That's, that's not missing.
That's late for dinner.
부서 전체를 동원하고 있네
We're mobilizing the whole department.
자네를 포함한 간부 전원을 불러냈어
We're pulling you
and every senior officer.
잠깐만요, 이 사람은 어떡합니까?
다리 밑으로 던져 버려요?
Wait, what am I supposed to do with him,
throw him under a bridge?
딴 데 넘겨 버려, 관심없네
Hand him off.
I don't really care.
나탈리
Natalie!
시장님이 20분 안에
시청으로 오라고 하셨네
The mayor wants you
at city hall in 20 minutes.
- 시장님이 절 직접 호출을?
- 모두 불렀어
- Wait, the mayor asked for me?
- He's asking for everybody.
실종된 판사 줄리언 가르랑
개인적으로 친하시거든
This judge, Jillian Garr,
is a close personal friend.
- 부국장님 차로 같이 갈까요?
- 저어, 의사 선생님
- Will you take me in your car?
- Excuse me, doctor.
- 잠깐 말씀 좀 드려도 되나요?
- 기다려 주시죠
- Can I talk to you?
- Can it wait?
속눈썹 하나를 발견했거든요
살인범의 것일 수도 있어요
I just found an eyelash.
It might belong to the killer.
- 부탁입니다, 정말 중요한 일이에요
- 얼마 안 걸립니다
- Please, it's very important.
- I'll be right with you.
선생님, 정말 다급해요
Sir, it really can't wait.
- 무슨 일이신데요?
- 저 열나는 것 같지 않나요?
- What is it?
- Do I feel warm to you?
어때요?
How am I?
이런! 화씨 99.9도네요
Huh! 99.9.
안 돼요
Oh, no.
안 돼
보세요, 딱 100이네요
이제 기분 좋으세요?
There you go.
An even 100. You happy?
줄리, 보지 마라
뒤로 돌아 있어
Julie, don't look.
Turn around.
딴 사람들 코 푸는 건
전에도 봤어요, 아저씨
I've seen people blow
their nose before, Mr. Monk.
- 됐죠, 치워 버릴게요
- 바깥에 버려요
- Okay, I'm gonna throw it away.
- Outside.
바깥, 알아요, 알아
Outside, I know, I know.
아저씨, 선물 사왔어요
열어 보세요
Mr. Monk, I bought
this for you. Open it.
음악 연주 칩이 들어 있어요
It has a musical chip in it.
고맙다
Thanks.
하지만, 난 로큰롤은 정말 싫은데
But, uh, I really don't
like the Rock 'n' Roll music.
아저씨, 로큰롤이긴요
"폴리 울리 두들"이잖아요
Mr. Monk, it's not Rock 'n' Roll.
It's polly wolly doodle.
10년은 가는 전지가 들어 있어요
It has a 10-year battery.
여기다 두면 어떨까요?
계속 보실 수 있게요
How about I put it over here,
so then you can see it?
엄마 도와드리러 가 봐야겠네요
I'm gonna go see
if my mom needs me.
뭐 하는 거예요?
What are you doing?
아무것도 아니에요
Oh, nothing.
아무것도 아녜요
Nothing.
뭘 숨겼어요?
What are you hiding?
아무것도 안 숨겼어요
I'm not hiding anything.
- 이 소리를 죽이려고 했어요?
- 아예 안 들리게 하려고 했죠
- Were you trying to muffle this?
- I was trying to kill it.
몽크 씨, 줄리가 자기 돈
털어 산 카드예요
Mr. Monk, Julie paid
for this with her own money.
뿌듯해 하고 있을 거라고요
She's so proud of it.
여기다 두면 잘 안 들릴 거예요
There, you can hardly hear it.
그만 푹 쉬어요, 알았죠?
Okay, I want you
to get some rest, all right?
쉬는 게 제일 좋은 약이에요
Rest is the best medicine.
아, 그래, 고맙다
금방 갔다 올게요
Oh, okay. Thank you, honey.
I will be right back.
아니, 잠깐만요
No, no, wait, wait, wait.
무슨 짓입니까? 어딜 가는데요?
What, what are you doing?
Where are you going?
경찰서에 급히 가봐야 해서요
I'm just gonna run up
to police headquarters.
살해당한 피자 배달원 얘길
반장님이랑 해야겠어요
I want to talk to the captain
about the man that was killed.
그 사람 죽은 게
나탈리 잘못도 아니잖아요
Natalie, Natalie,
that wasn't your fault.
알아요, 몽크 씨
I know, Mr. Monk.
하지만, 그 사람이 살아 있는 걸
마지막으로 본 사람이 저라고요
But I was the last person
to see him alive.
그런 게 어떤 의미인지
예전엔 전혀 생각도 못했는데
I never really thought
about what that means.
중요한 의미가 있는 일이더군요
You know? But it means something.
거참 신기하죠
책임감 같은 게 느껴지거든요
It's weird, I feel kind of responsible.
날 여기다 놔두고 가면 안 돼요
No, you, you can't just leave me here.
괜찮아요, 줄리가
지키고 있을 테니까요
No, you're gonna be okay.
Julie will be here.
코를 풀어야 하면 어떡하고요?
But what if I have
to blow my nose again?
비닐봉지에 어떻게 넣는지
가르쳐 줬어요
I showed her how to do the bags.
휴대전화도 있고요
금방 갔다 올게요
I have my phone.
I will be right back.
잘 지내 봐요
Good luck, guys.
저거, 음...
That's, uh...
줄리, 두 번째 서랍에 보면
편지지가 있단다
Julie, there's a pad in that second drawer.
종이랑 펜을 갖다줄래?
Can you get the pad and pen?
내가 말하는 걸 전부 받아 적으렴
Write down everything I say.
- 편지 쓰시게요?
- 아니, 편지는 아니고
- Is it a letter?
- No, it's not exactly a letter.
우리 어른들이 생전 유서라고
부르는 거란다
It's what we grownups call a living will.
판사님이 만나는 사람이 있었나?
Was she dating?
- 남자 친구는 있었나?
- 우리가 아는 한은 없어요
- Does she have a boyfriend?
- No, not that we know of.
글쎄, 확인해 봐
Well, find out for sure.
통화 기록이랑
카드 영수증도 살펴보고
Check her phone records,
credit card receipts.
적어도 12개월 이내에 나온
모든 걸 확인해 보라고
Go back at least 12 months
on everything.
여기 있는 모두가
최선을 다해 찾도록 해
I want everybody's best game here.
- 이건 뭔가?
- 원한을 품었던 놈입니다
- What's that?
- A guy with a grudge.
존 딜랜시입니다
이혼 소송에 휘말려 있었는데
John Delancey.
He's going through a messy divorce.
가르 판사가 3주 전에
불리한 판결을 내렸죠
Judge Garr ruled against him
three weeks ago.
법정에서 판사에게 소리지르기
시작해서 구금해야만 했습니다
He started screaming at her in court.
They had to restrain him.
이런, 차도 망가뜨렸군
Why, he hit her car.
아마도 사고였을 겁니다
Maybe. There was an incident.
법원을 나오고 있었는데
Uh, as she was leaving the courthouse,
차끼리 충돌했죠
가벼운 접촉 사고 같아요
their cars collided,
like a little fender-bender.
심하게 처박았잖아
이게 단순 사고였다고?
He rammed her car.
Was it an accident?
3명의 목격자를 확보했지만
아무도 확신은 못 했죠
We've got three witnesses,
but nobody's sure.
저희가 아는 한 판사님도
보고를 하거나 고발하진 않았고요
All we know is she didn't
report it or press charges.
어쨌든 이놈을 찾아내
Well, you find this guy.
Find him.
반장님
Captain.
나탈리, 보시다시피
여긴 지금 미쳐 돌아가고 있답니다
Natalie, look,
it's kind of crazy right now.
- 우리 환자는 좀 어때요?
- 독감이더군요
- Say, how's our patient?
- He has the flu.
- 그래서 어쩌고 있습니까?
- 쫑알대서 아주 돌아버리겠어요
- What's he doing about it?
- Complaining. Driving me nuts.
훌리오 알바레즈 건은
어떻게 돼 가요?
Any news on the Julio Alvarez case?
에, 디셔에게 물어보시죠
Um, ask Disher about that.
반장님이 경위님더러 제게
대신 설명해주라고 하시던데요
Lieutenant, the captain
said you would fill me in.
글쎄요, 별로 아는 게 없습니다
Yeah, well, we don't know much.
판사님에겐 해변 별장이 있는데
She owns a beach house.
지금은 감식반을 하나 더 불러
거기에 보내 놓았죠
We're sending another
forensics team down there now.
판사 사건 말고 딴 사건이요
알바레즈 말이에요
Not the judge, the other case.
Alvarez.
- 누구요?
- 훌리오 알바레즈요
- Who?
- Julio Alvarez.
제 말 끝낼 틈도 없이 물으시네요
누구죠 알바레즈가?
You didn't let me finish.
Who-lio Alvarez?
- 피자 배달원 말이에요
- 아, 맞아요
- The delivery guy.
- Yeah, right.
젠킨스, 누가 피자 사건 맡았지?
Jenkins, who caught the pizza thing?
피자 사건이라니요?
그 사람도 이름은 있어요
The pizza thing?
He had a name, Randy.
판사 같은 고귀하신 몸은 아니지만
어엿한 이름이 있다고요
He might not have been a judge,
but he had a name.
보세요, 저도 이런 게
정말 싫습니다, 싫다고요
Hey, I resent that.
I really do.
여기선 모든 사건이 다 중요하죠
좋아하는 것만 골라 수사하진 않아요
Every case is important here.
We don't play favorites.
알았어요
Okay.
- 여기 수사 파일을 갖다 놨습니다
- 잘됐네요
- I've got the file right here.
- That's all right.
어딘가에 있을 텐데
Somewhere.
경사, 알바레즈 사건 파일 봤나?
Sergeant, have you seen
the Alvarez file?
그럼요, 방금 봤어요
Yeah, I just saw it.
이게 누구죠?
Who's this?
피해자 아닙니까
훌리오 알바레즈요
That's the victim.
Julio Alvarez.
아닌데요
No.
이 사람이 아니에요
No, this isn't the guy.
나탈리, 이 사람 맞아요
Natalie, that's the guy.
직원 신분증이 있고요
There's his employee I.D.
시신은 공시소에 있어요
He's dead. He's in the morgue.
저희 집 문 앞에 왔던 사람은 아니에요
That's not the man
that came to the door.
자, 보세요, 어젯밤에
아주 잠깐 보기만 하셨댔죠
Okay, look, you said you only
got a glimpse of him last night.
이 사람이 맞아요
그거 판사 집에서 나온 거 맞지?
I mean, that's the guy.
Is that from the judge's house?
- 예
- 반장님 자리로 보내
- Yeah.
- Captain's office.
이만 가볼게요
I gotta go.
이 사람이 아니야
That's not the guy.
이봐요, 경찰에게 다 얘기했어요
거의 알지도 못하는 애라고요
Look, I already talked to the cops.
I barely knew the kid.
2주나 3주 전쯤
일을 시작했거든요
He started, like,
two or three weeks ago.
조의를 표하는 사진은커녕
꽃도 안 놓으셨네요?
You didn't put his picture up or flowers?
사장이 이 모든 걸
티 내지 말길 바란다고요
The boss wanted us to
downplay the whole thing.
- 장사가 안 되기 때문이라나요
- 보세요, 고먼 씨
- Said it was bad for business.
- Look, Mr. Gorman,
어젯밤 저희 집에 왔던 배달부가
훌리오 알바레즈인 것 같지 않아요
I'm not sure the man who came to my
house last night was Julio alvarez.
알바레즈 아니면 그럼 누구겠소?
Sure it was.
Who else could it be?
- 나탈리 티저 맞죠?
- 티거예요
- Natalie Teejer?
- Teeger.
페페로니에 치즈 토핑 추가
주문 맞습니까? / 맞아요
Pepperoni, extra cheese?
Is that you? / Yeah.
제가 직접 차에 실어 주고
그 애가 운전해 갔다오
I put it in the car,
the kid drove away.
- 혼자서요?
- 당연히 혼자 갔죠
- Was he alone?
- Sure he was alone.
이봐, 토미!
칼조네엔 마늘 너무 넣지 마!
Hey, Tommy!
Not too much garlic on the calzone!
알았어요!
Okay, okay!
- 잠깐 제가 봐도 될까요?
- 왜요?
- Hey, can I see those?
- Why?
저희 집에 오기 전에
어딜 갔는지 알고 싶어요
I'd like to see where he went
before he got to my house.
- 경찰이슈?
- 아뇨
- Are you a cop?
- No.
나도 일해야 하는데
어떻게 보여 줍니까?
Because I got work to do.
보세요, 경찰은 아니지만
탐정을 도와 일한다고요
Well, I'm not a cop,
but I work for a detective.
- 에이드리안 몽크요
- 누구요?
- Adrian Monk.
- Who?
에이드리안 몽크요
Adrian Monk.
그분은 진짜 명탐정이에요
천재라고요
He's a great detective.
He's, like, a genius.
아무한테나 물어 보세요
You can ask anybody.
잠시만요
Hold on.
아, 마침 그분 전화네요
기다리세요, 제가 통화하게 해드리죠
Ah, this is him now.
Stay here. I want him to talk to you.
- 여보세요
- 나탈리이...
- Hello.
- Natalie...
나탈리, 나에요
에이드리안 몽크예요
Natalie, it is me, Adrian Monk.
예, 안 그래도 몽크 씨 얘길
하고 있었어요
Yes, Mr. Monk.
We were just talking about you.
나탈리, 얼른 돌아와요
Natalie, you have to come back.
몽크 씨, 지금은 안 돼요
Mr. Monk, I can't right now.
피자집에 와서
지배인이랑 얘기 중이에요
I'm at the pizzeria,
talking to the manager.
에볼라예요
It's ebola.
뭐라고요?
Excuse me?
에볼라 바이러스에 감염됐어요
I have the ebola virus.
몽크 씨, 에볼라 바이러스에
걸린 건 아니에요
Mr. Monk, you don't
have the ebola virus.
아니, 틀림없다니까요
Oh, I'm pretty sure I do.
모든 증상이 들어맞다고요
I have all the symptoms.
열이랑 두통, 대량 내출혈까지
보이고 있어요
I have the fever and the headache
and the massive internal bleeding.
내출혈이 있다고요?
You have massive internal bleeding?
그런 것 같아요
I believe I do.
제 생각이 그렇다는 거죠
That is my opinion.
아뇨, 몽크 씨, 그냥 독감이에요
No, Mr. Monk, you have the flu.
하지만, 전화해 줘서 고마워요
But I'm glad you called.
매니저인 고먼 씨랑 얘기 중인데요
I'm talking to Mr. Gorman.
He's the manager.
잠깐 기다려요
Hold on.
여보세요
Hello.
모르겠는데요
I don't know.
- 애틀랜타에 있는 거 아니오?
- 무슨 얘길 하는데요?
- I think they're in Atlanta.
- What's he talking about?
질병 관리국에 대해 물어보는데요
He's asking about the center
for disease control.
훌리오는 좋은 놈이었어요
Hey, Julio was a good guy.
행운을 빌어요
Good luck.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
딜랜시, 존 딜랜시요
Delancey. John Delancey.
있는 줄 다 압니다
비서랑 방금 얘기하고 왔어요
We know he's in there.
We just talked to his assistant.
회원 전용 클럽이니
양해해 주셨으면 합니다
You understand
this is a private club.
영장이 없이는 안 됩니다
Unless you have a warrant...
그럼 이러는 건 어떻겠소?
Well, how about this?
여기서 기다릴 테니 가서
그자를 불러 오시오
We wait here, and you
go in there and get him.
그럴 수는 없습니다
I can't do that.
안 된다는 거요
못 하겠다는 거요?
Can't or won't?
양쪽 다 조금씩 해당하죠
A little of each.
딜랜시는 6번 테이블에 있군
Delancey, table six.
자리 배치도에서 6번은...
Seating chart, table six.
저기 있군요
Over there.
일어나지 마시오
Don't get up.
난 강력반의 리랜드 스토틀마이어고
이쪽은 디셔 경위요
I'm Leland Stottlemeyer, homicide.
This is lieutenant Disher.
줄리언 가르에 대해 묻고
싶은 게 있소 / 누구요?
We wanna talk to you
about Jillian Garr. / Who?
줄리언 가르 판사 말이오
Judge Jillian Garr.
댁이 법정에서 위협한 사람이자
You threatened her in court,
주차장에서 댁의 차로
갖다 박은 차의 주인이죠
and then you rammed her car
in a parking lot.
이젠 행방이 묘연하고요
And now she's missing.
무슨 소리를 하는 겁니까?
What are you talking about?
반장님
Captain.
기다려 봐, 랜디
Hang on, Randy.
넥타이 빠진 음식 좋아하시오?
Hey, you like Tie food?
응?
Huh?
이젠 좀 기억이 나시나?
How's your memory now?
반장님, 여기가 6번이 아닙니다
Captain, this isn't table six.
자리 배치도를 거꾸로 봤어요
Chart was upside down.
음...
Um...
저기...
I, uh...
죄송합니다
I'm sorry.
실수를 했군요
I, um, I made a mistake.
다른 분과 착각했습니다
I thought you were somebody else.
저기...
Uh, hey, look.
여기...
Uh, here.
제 넥타이를 대신 매시죠
Take my, my tie.
이래봬도...
This is a...
100달러나 줬습니다
it's a $100 tie.
크리스마스 선물이거든요
It was a Christmas gift, okay?
여기요
There.
썩 꺼지시오
Get out of here.
나중에 나랑 면담 좀 하지
6번 테이블은 어딘가?
We'll talk about this later.
Where is table six?
예, 음...
Okay, uh...
잠깐만요
Hold on.
여기가 창문이니까...
Here's the window.
이런
Oh.
실수했네요
저기가 6번 맞습니다
My bad. That was table six.
원래 맞았던 거예요
I was right.
확실한가?
Are you sure?
예
Yeah.
이봐, 방금 내 넥타이까지 건네줬네
Look, I just gave him my tie.
게다가 이제 내 말이
별로 권위가 없어 보일 거라고
Plus I've lost a little bit
of authority with him.
- 안 그럴걸요
- 안 그럴 거 같다고?
- No, I don't think so.
- No, you don't think so?
저분도 이해해 주겠죠 뭐
Well, I'm sure he'll understand.
누구나 실수는 하잖습니까
Everybody makes mistakes, sir.
재차 안녕하시오
Hello again. Um...
좀 황당하시겠지만
내 넥타이를 돌려받고 싶군요
This is a little embarrassing,
but I'm gonna have to ask for my tie back.
나한테 줬잖아요
You gave it to me.
글쎄, 이런 멋진 넥타이를
매려고 했다면
Well, look, if you're gonna wear
such a nice tie,
제대로 매어야지
you gotta wear it straight.
이렇게 비뚤게 매면 안 되지
You don't wear a nice tie
like that crooked.
좋소, 어디까지 했죠?
Okay now, where were we?
아, 줄리언 가르 얘길 하고 있었지
Yeah, we were talking
about Jillian Garr.
그 여자 때문에
250만 달러를 물었어요
She cost me $2.5 million.
인정합니다, 화가 났었습니다
I admit it.
I lost my temper.
판사님 차에 돌진했고요
You rammed her car.
누굴 해칠 의도는 아니었어요
그냥 열 받아 그랬다고요
I wasn't trying to hurt anybody.
I was pissed off.
형사님들은 엉뚱한 것만
물어보고 계시는군요
You know, you boys are asking
the wrong question here.
"왜 판사가 고발을 안 했지?"
같은 걸 물어보셔야죠
You should be asking
"why didn't she press charges?"
좋아요, 그럼 왜 고발을 안 했죠?
Okay, why didn't she press charges?
왜냐면 동행이 있었거든요
Because she wasn't alone.
여자랑 같이 탄 남자가 있었죠
두 연놈이 입맞추는 걸 봤어요
There was a man with her in the car.
I saw them kissing.
내가 여자 차를 받으니
남자는 내려서 도망가더군요
When I hit her, he got out and ran.
눈에 띄고 싶지 않았나 보네요
He didn't want to be seen.
유부남이었겠군
He was married.
- 기혼남을 만나고 있었던 거야
- 추측 한번 잘하셨어요
- She was seeing a married guy.
- Good guess.
이제 웨이터를 불러 주시겠소?
Now, could you find my waiter?
요리를 새로 갖다 달래야죠
I'm going to need another plate.
수프 드세요
Eat your soup.
- 글자가 막 보여요
- 알파벳 수프니까요
- I see letters.
- Yeah, it's alphabet soup.
"A" / 글자 순서대로
드실 필요 없어요
"A." / You don't have to eat it in order.
줄리가 준 카드 어디 있어요?
Where's Julie's card?
쓰레기통에 집어넣었죠
I put it in the recycle bin.
방금 수거해 갔어요
They just collected it.
줄리가 얼마나 뿌듯해 하던 건데!
걔한테 뭐라고 하면 좋아요
Julie is so proud of that card.
What am I supposed to tell her?
재활용이 중요한 일이라고 해 줘요
Tell her that recycling is important.
그렇게 서로 도와서
지구를 구하는 거라고요
And that together,
we're saving the planet.
"B" / 사건 얘기 조금만 해도 될까요?
"B." / Can I just talk about
the case for one minute please?
제가 좀 생각해 봤는데요
So I've been thinking about this.
배달 온 남자는 야구 모자랑
선글라스를 쓰고 있었어요
The man at the door was wearing
a baseball cap and sunglasses.
야밤에 선글라스를요
Sunglasses at night.
제가 얼굴을 보지 못하게
숨기려고 했던 것 같아요
It was like he was trying
to hide his face from me.
중요한 거라고 생각지 않으세요?
Do you think it means something?
모르겠어요
I don't know.
괜히 놀랐네
"Q"가 부러진 거군요
False alarm. That's a broken "Q."
몽크 씨, 제겐 정말 중요한 일이에요
Mr. Monk, this is important to me.
자, 그 사람은 7시 5분에
피자집을 나와서
All right, so he left the pizzeria at 7:05.
7시 40분까지 저희 집에 안 왔고
피자는 다 식어 있었죠, 기억나세요?
He didn't get here until 7:40,
and the pizza was cold, remember?
- 식었어요
- 예, 맞아요
- Cold.
- Yeah, that's right.
그게 뭘 뜻하는 거라 생각하세요?
What do you think it means?
식었어요
Cold.
중요한 사실 같으세요?
Do you think it's important?
몸이 식고 있어요
I'm so cold.
우리 집에 오기 전에
두 곳을 더 들렀어요
All right, he had two other
stops before he got here.
배달 주소들을 알아냈으니
그 사람 간 곳을 재추적할 거예요
I got the addresses.
I'm gonna retrace his steps.
안 돼, 안돼요
No, no, no, no.
안돼요, 나탈리
No, Natalie.
경찰이 알아서 하게 내버려 둬요
Just let the police handle it.
이 젊은 애는 신경도 안 써줘요
이름조차 기억 못 하던데요
They don't care about this kid.
They can't even remember his name.
제 의견도 전혀 귀담아듣지 않고요
And they sure as hell don't
care about what I think.
다들 실종된 판사만 신경 쓰고 있어요
All they care about is this missing judge.
몽크 씨, 저랑 같이 가 주세요
Mr. Monk, I need you to come with me.
- 안 돼요
- 괜찮아요, 갈 수 있어요
- I can't.
- Yes, you can. You can rally.
미치는 미식축구 선수였어요
Hey, Mitch was a football player.
선수들은 몸 성할 날이 없었죠
Players got injured all the time.
"훌륭한 선수는 몸이 아파도 경기해"
라고 입버릇처럼 말했죠
He always said,
"the great ones play hurt."
몽크 씨 없이 저 혼자선
이 사건을 해결 못 해요
Mr. Monk, I can't do this without you.
차에 앉아만 있어요
겨우 한 시간 거리예요
Just sit in the car.
It'll just take an hour.
못 해요
I can't.
됐어요, 저 가요
여기 왔던 사람이 죽었어요
Well, I'm going.
A man was killed, and he was here.
뭐라도 해야겠어요
I have to do something.
안돼요, 나탈리
No, no. Natalie.
나탈리, 가지 말아요
Natalie, you can't go.
그냥 가면 안 돼요
You can't just leave.
1번 가습기에 물이 없잖아요
Vaporizer one is empty.
얼었다 녹은 것처럼 추워요
I'm almost out of ice.
절 봐주는 게 나탈리 일이잖아요
You have to do your job.
미안해요, 몽크 씨
안 되겠네요
I'm sorry, Mr. Monk.
I can't.
봐 드리기엔 너무 바쁘거든요
I'm too busy doing your job.
얘들이 자고 간대서
They were having a sleepover.
피자 세 판을 시켜 줬어요
We ordered three pizzas.
- 하와이안 하나, 페페로니 하나...
- 야채 피자 하나요
- One Hawaiian, one pepperoni.
- And one veggie master.
배달부가 이 사람인가요?
Is this him?
확실하세요?
Are you sure?
예, 경찰이 왔었어요
똑같은 사진을 들고 왔죠
Yeah, the police were here.
They had the same picture.
이 사람이 확실해요
That's definitely him.
정말 안됐더군요
We felt terrible about it.
모자나 선글라스를 쓰고 있었나요?
Was he wearing a hat or sunglasses?
아뇨
No.
- 안녕하세요
Hello. / Hi.
무슨 일이시죠?
Can I help you?
방해해서 죄송해요
곤란한 때가 아니라면 좋겠네요
Sorry to bother you.
I hope this isn't a bad time.
음, 사실은 다른 일을
좀 하는 중이라서요
Uh, as a matter of fact,
I'm sort of in the middle of something.
왜요? 뭣 때문에 그러시죠?
Why?
What is all this about?
방해해서 정말 죄송해요
전 몇 블록 떨어진 데 사는데요 / 예
Really sorry to bother you.
I live a few blocks away. / Yeah.
이 동네에서 본 적이 있어요
I've seen you around.
예
Yeah.
제 고양이 백설 공주가 도망가서요
it's about my cat snowflake.
She's run away.
고양이요
Your cat.
혹시 사진 있으신가요?
Do you have a picture?
아뇨, 그게 들인 지 얼마 안 돼서...
No, see, that's the thing.
She's new. So...
어쨌든 고마워요
방해해서 죄송합니다
Thanks anyway.
Sorry to bother you.
잠깐만요
Hold on.
이거 아세요?
제가 고양이 하나를 찾았거든요
You know what?
I did find a cat.
오늘 아침에 우리 집 앞문을
긁고 있더군요
This morning.
She was scratching my front door.
지하실에 놔뒀어요
She's down in the basement.
- 들어와 보세요
- 아뇨, 제 고양이가 아닐 거예요
- Come on in.
- No, it's probably not her.
- 무슨 색이었는데요?
- 흰색이요
- What color is it?
- White.
제 고양이일 리 없어요
백설 공주는 검은색이에요
See, it can't be her.
Snowflake's black.
'백설 공주'가 검은색이라니?
Snowflake is black?
어쨌든 고마워요
Thanks anyway.
그 엄지손가락에
얼음찜질을 꼭 하세요
You really should put
some ice on that thumb.
그 사람이 어쨌다고요?
He had a what?
엄지손가락에 타박상이 있어요
A bruise on his thumb.
같은 상처를 입은 사람이 줄리가
주문한 피자를 배달했다고요
I remember the guy that delivered
Julie's pizza had the same bruise.
자기 집으로 끌어들이려고 하던데요
He tried to get me in his house.
나탈리가 맘에 들었나 보죠
Maybe he likes you.
나탈리에게 매력을 느꼈나 봐요
첫눈에 반하는 일도 있잖아요
Maybe he finds you attractive.
Stranger things have happened.
아뇨, 절 죽이고 싶어 했어요
장담할 수 있어요
No, he wanted to kill me.
I can tell.
수색 영장을 청구할 수 없을까요?
Can't you get a search warrant?
그런 거 가지고는 안 돼요
No, not based on this.
그 남자는 좋은 집도 있고
돈도 좀 있지 않나요?
I mean, the guy's got a nice house, right?
And he's got some money?
뭐 하러 피자 배달원을 살해하겠어요?
Why would he kill a pizza delivery guy?
- 이유야 모르죠
- 하물며 배달원을 죽였다 쳐도
- I don't know.
- Even if he did kill him,
뭐 하러 동네를 가로질러 달려서
줄리가 시킨 피자를 배달해요?
why would he drive across town
and deliver Julie's pizza to her?
이치에 닿지 않아요
It doesn't make sense.
적어도 이쪽으로 오셔서
그 사람이랑 말해 보시면 안 돼요?
Well, can't you at least
come down here and talk to him?
예, 2시간 있다 가겠습니다
Yeah, I can be there in two hours.
안 돼요! 그때쯤이면
도주하고 없을지도 몰라요
No, no! He could be gone by then.
반장님 어디 계세요?
Where's the captain?
사건 수사 중이십니다
He's working on the case.
나탈리 사건 말고 딴 거요
큰 사건 말입니다
Not your case, the other case.
The big case.
판사는 4시 45분에 법원을 떠났어
She left the courthouse at 4:45.
101번 도로를 달려 북쪽으로 가는 게
여기서 감시 카메라에 찍혔다네
She was last seen driving north on the 101
by a surveillance camera right here.
차에는 혼자 있었어
She was alone in the car.
지도가 딱 중간에 놓여 있지 않군요
It's not centered.
저거요
That one.
됐어요, 좋아요
Good. Good.
판사의 차는 이곳
주차장에서 발견되었네
Okay now, her car was found
in a parking lot here.
잠겨 있지 않은 데다
아주 싹 청소를 했더군
It was unlocked.
It had been wiped clean.
지문도 섬유도 남아 있지 않았어
There were no prints, no fibers.
여기 촬영된 걸 갖고 왔네
I got some photographs here.
이런, 잠깐만요
Oh, no, wait.
눈이 안 보여요
초점이 안 맞아요
I can't see. I can't focus.
- 볼 수가 없어요
- 그럼 사진은 나중에 보게
- I can't see.
- Okay, you'll look at the pictures later.
이것 좀 돌려주실래요?
Could you turn this?
고마워요, 됐어요
Thank you.
Well, that's good.
이건 뭐야?
What is this thing?
가습기요
It's a humidifier.
저건 뭐고?
What's that one?
제습기요
It's a dehumidifier.
뭐야, 두 개의 효과가
서로 상쇄되지 않나? / 맞습니다
Well, don't they cancel each other out?
Exactly.
누군가를 만나고 있었다는 걸 알아냈네
유부남인 것 같아
Um, we know that she was seeing
somebody. He might be married.
신용 카드 기록에서 보듯이
You can tell by her credit card records
2월에 같이 여행을 갔네
that they went on a trip
together in February.
오클리, 아이다호에 2월 10일부터
2주간 가 있었지
They went to Oakley, Idaho
February 10th, for two weeks.
결혼한 사람이 아닙니다
He's not married.
- 미혼남이라고?
- 예
- He's not married?
- No.
그걸 어떻게 아나?
How do you know that?
몽크, 미혼이란 걸 어떻게 알았나?
Monk, how do you know
he's not married?
발렌타인데이에 거길 갔잖습니까
Well, they were there on Valentine's day.
결혼한 몸이라면 집에 있었겠죠
If he was married,
he would've stayed home.
자네 말이 옳아
Yep, you're right.
봉지가 필요해요
I need a baggie.
서랍 안에 있어요
They're in the drawer.
몽크, 이 사건에 집중해 주겠나?
Monk, can you focus here please?
알았어, 알았다고
Okay, okay, okay.
몽크, 사건에 집중해 봐
Monk, focus here, would you?
- 밀봉하세요
- 어째서...
Zip it. / Why...
- 밀봉하시라니까요
- 어째서 비밀로 했을까?
- You gotta zip it.
- Why keep it a secret?
봉지가 또 하나 있어야 돼요
I'm gonna need another baggie.
그 봉지를 다른 봉지에 담으세요
You're gonna put this baggie
into another baggie.
- 이 큰 봉지?
- 그거요
- This big baggie?
- That's...
그래, 몽크, 정신을 놓지 말게
Okay, Monk, stay with me here, okay?
판사 아닙니까
She's a judge.
그러니 그, 애인이
사회 통념상 절대로...
So maybe he was someone
that she was not allowed...
만나선 안 될 남자였을지도 모르지
to see socially.
그래, 판사가 맡은 소송에
참가하고 있는 변호사라면
Yes, like a lawyer is someone who
might be involved in one of her cases.
이해관계가 충돌하니까
A conflict of interest.
공기를 확실하게 빼 주세요
Make sure it's airtight.
밀봉도 해 주시고요
나탈리는 두 번씩 접었어요
You gotta zip it.
Natalie usually folds it twice.
일단 밀봉한 다음
접으시면 돼요
First you zip it.
Then you fold it.
먼저, 공기부터 다 빼야죠
First you gotta get the air out.
먼저, 공기를 빼셔야 해요
공기부터요
You gotta let the air out first.
Let the air out first.
몽크, 내가 전혀 티를 내지 않았으니
자넨 눈치도 못 챘을 테지만
Monk, I know you probably can't tell
because I'm hiding it so well,
난 이런 일이 정말 지긋지긋하네
but I really don't like this.
예, 여보세요
Yeah, hello.
몽크 씨, 줄리가 시킨 피자를
배달한 남자를 찾아냈어요
Mr. Monk, I found the guy
who delivered Julie's pizza.
범인이 틀림없어요
이름은 레지 데니슨이에요
It's definitely him.
His name is Reggie Dennison.
나탈리, 내가 계속 전화했잖아요
Uh, Natalie, I've been calling you.
알아요, 일부러 안 받았어요
I know. I didn't answer.
저더러 이 일에서 빠지라고
설득하려던 거죠?
I knew you'd try
to talk me out of this.
이 일이라뇨?
Out of what?
놈의 집 안에 들어왔어요
I'm in his house.
놈의 집에 들어갔다고요?
You're in his house?
차에 뭔가를 싣더라고요
He put something in his car.
뭔지는 파악 못 했어요
차를 몰고 사라졌거든요
I couldn't make it out.
And then he drove off.
놈의 집에 들어갔다고요?
You're in his house?
달리 방도가 안 떠올랐어요
아무도 제 말을 귀담아듣지 않잖아요
I didn't know what else to do.
No one was listening to me.
나탈리, 그놈 집에 있어요?
Oh, Natalie, you're in his house?
잘 들어요
Listen.
얼른 나와요
Get outta there.
그리고...
And...
오는 길에 기침 가라앉히는
사탕도 사다 주고요
Can you pick up some cough drops
on your way back?
일단은 거기서 나와요
But get outta there!
사탕 잊지 말고요
Don't forget the cough drops.
- 찾아낼 때까지는 안 나가요
- 뭘 찾아요?
- I'm not leaving here until I find it.
- Find what?
저도 몰라요, 모르지만
증거를 찾아야 해요
I don't know. I don't know.
I just, I need proof.
몽크 씨, 조금만 도와 줘요
뭘 찾아야 하는지 모르겠어요
Mr. Monk, just please help me.
I don't know what I'm looking for.
벽난로가 있네요
The fireplace.
뭔가를 태우고 있었어요
잠깐, 끊지 말아요
He was burning something.
Hold on, hold on.
하나 찾아냈어요, 놈이에요
There's one. It's him.
여자랑 있는데 누군지는 모르겠어요
He's with a woman,
but I can't make it out.
오클리 인이라는 호텔에 있었네요
They're at a hotel, the Oakley inn.
어디요, 오클리 인?
Whoa, uh, Oakley inn?
오클리 인이라
Oakley inn.
나탈리, 저기
Natalie, is,
그자가 변호사인가요?
is this guy a lawyer?
예, 그걸 어떻게 알았어요?
- 휘틀리 대학 법학과 -
Okay now, how did you know that?
Whitley University School Of Law
무슨 냄새가 나는데요
I smell something.
표백제예요
It's bleach.
저 욕실에 왔어요
Okay, I'm in the bathroom.
막 청소를 했나 봐요
He must have just cleaned it.
냄새가 마치...
It smells like...
몽크 씨 욕실 냄새 같네요
it smells like your bathroom.
핏자국 같은 건 없어요?
Is, is, is there blood?
음...
Um...
없어요
no.
이상한데요
욕조 커튼이 없어요
That's weird.
There's no shower curtain.
벽에 불 켜는 스위치 있죠?
Is there a light switch on the wall?
있어요
Yes.
- 켜져 있어요, 꺼져 있어요?
- 꺼져 있네요
- Is it on or off?
- It's off.
그럼 불을 켜요
Well, switch it on.
조심해요
물티슈 같은 걸 써요
Be careful.
Use a wipe or something.
핏자국이에요
It's blood.
그러면 그렇지, 다들 꼭
불 켜는 스위치는 잊고 안 닦는다니까
Oh, yeah, they always
forget the light switch.
나탈리, 진상은 이런 거예요
Natalie, Natalie,
here's what happened.
이 데니슨이란 변호사는
This lawyer, Dennison,
가르 판사랑 놀아나고 있었죠
was having an affair with judge Garr.
어젯밤에 판사가 놈의 집에 왔어요
She came to his house last night.
시간이 좀 지나고 나서
피자를 시켜 먹기로 했죠
And at some point they
decided to order a pizza.
뭔가 일이 안 좋게 흘러가서
Somehow things turned ugly.
둘이 심하게 다투었을 거예요
뭣 때문이었는지는 모르지만요
Maybe they had a fight.
We'll probably never know
what it was about.
어쨌든 놈은 판사를 죽였어요
But he killed her.
욕실에서 살해한 거죠
He killed her in that bathroom.
하지만, 배달부 훌리오가...
But the delivery guy Julio...
공격하는 장면을 봤거나
소리를 듣고 말았던 거예요
must have seen
the attack or heard something.
아마도 여자를 구하려다가
And he tried to help her.
그 와중에 목숨을 잃었겠지요
He died trying to save her.
나탈리, 기침 가라앉히는
사탕이 있어야겠어요
Natalie, I'm gonna need
those cough drops.
"멘톨" 말고요
제가 먹는 종류 아시죠?
Not the menthol.
You, you, you know the kind.
어쨌든 데니슨는 난처하게 되었어요
Anyway, Dennison had a problem.
피자집에선 훌리오의
배달처를 다 알고 있고
The pizzeria knew Julio's route.
훌리오가 그냥 사라지면
경찰은 데니슨에게
And Dennison knew that
if Julio just disappeared,
혐의를 둘 게 뻔했죠
the cops would focus on him.
주변을 비집고 다니면서
질문을 해댈 게 뻔했어요
They'd poke around.
They'd ask a lot of questions.
그래서 제3자가
So he needed somebody else
살아있는 훌리오를 마지막으로
보길 원했던 겁니다
to be the last person
who saw Julio alive.
놈은 훌리오인 체하고
피자 하나를 배달하기로 했죠
He decided to deliver
one more pizza as Julio,
놈에게서 주의를 돌리기 위해서요
to divert attention from himself.
나탈리 말이 맞았어요
You were right, Natalie.
피자 배달을 왔던 건
훌리오가 아니었어요
Julio didn't deliver that pizza.
그 친구를 죽인 놈이 배달한 거죠
The man who killed him did.
영리한 놈이지만
두 가지 실수를 저질렀죠
He was smart,
but he made two mistakes.
아주 큰 실수요
Big mistakes.
하나는 나탈리가 찾아낸
욕실 조명 스위치에 묻은 핏자국
One, that blood you found
on the bathroom light switch.
그게 판사의 피라면요
내 생각도 그래요
If that's the judge's blood,
and I think it is,
평생 옥살이를 해야 할 겁니다
he's going to jail for life.
하지만, 핏자국이 없다 해도
놈을 단죄할 수 있어요
But even without that blood,
we can still convict him.
2번째 실수는...
Mistake number two,
놈이 배달한 피자 상자에
온통 지문이 묻어 있겠죠
his fingerprints are all over
that pizza box he delivered.
쓰레기장에 있을 거예요
It's at the recycling dump.
찾아내려고만 하면
찾아낼 수 있겠죠
I'm sure they can find it
if they have to.
오늘 아침에 막 수거해 갔으니까요
They just collected it this morning.
아, 딴 전화가 왔어요
끊지 말아요
Oh, that's my other line, hold on.
몽크 씨!
Mr. Monk.
나탈리, 나중에 다시 전화할게요
통화 중이거든요
Yeah, Natalie, I'll call you back.
I'm on the other line.
말하지 말아요
Don't...
어디까지 했더라?
Where was I?
나탈리?
Natalie?
나탈리!
괜찮아요?
Are you okay?
한 마디라도 남에게 지껄였다간
Say one word to anybody,
여자는 죽는다, 알아들었나?
she's dead. Understand?
살려 주세요
아직 어린 딸이 있어요
Please, I have a daughter.
그걸 찾는 걸 도와
그럼 딸은 다시 볼지도 모르지
Help me find it,
maybe you'll see her again.
- 뭘 찾아요?
- 상자! 피자 상자 말이야!
Find what?
The box! The box!
내 지문이 묻은 피자 상자!
The pizza box with my prints on it.
어디에 담아 버렸어?
골판지 상자야, 봉지야?
What was it in?
A carton, a bag, or what?
제 고용주가
재활용 쓰레기로 버렸어요
My boss recycled it.
뭐든지 20인치 높이로
쌓아 분류하거든요
He separates everything into
piles exactly 20 inches high.
그런 다음 각각의 쓰레기 더미를
Then he puts each pile into a green,
10갤런 크기의 두 겹짜리
강화 쓰레기봉투에 담아
10-gallon reinforced
double-ply trash bag,
테이프로 두 번 붙여서 밀봉해요
which he double-tapes shut.
그런 다음 그 봉투를
또 다른 봉투에 넣고
Then he puts that bag into another bag,
노끈을 반시계방향으로 4번 돌려
싼 다음 각각 두 번씩 매듭져요
which he wraps with twine four times
counterclockwise and ties each end twice.
- 그걸 다 마친 다음...
- 날 갖고 놀려는 수작이지?
- Once he's completed that...
- Are you screwing with me?
아뇨, 정말 우리 고용주는
장난 아니게 까다로운걸요
No, I swear.
He's very persnickety.
알았어
All right.
오늘 아침에 수거해 갔댔지
He said that it was
picked up this morning.
저기부터 시작하지
We'll start there.
여길 찾아
Look down here.
안 보이는데요
I don't see it.
- 시간 벌려는 속셈이군
- 하느님께 맹세코 아니에요
- You're stalling.
- I'm not. I swear to god.
그 망할 상자를 찾는 걸 도울
기회를 한 번 더 주겠다
I'm gonna give you one more chance
to help me find the damn box.
우리가 뒤를 맡을게요
We'll take the back.
몽크는 어디 있나?
Where is Monk?
- 어디 있어?
- 일으켜 봐
- Where is he?
- Get him up.
몽크 어디 있어?
Where is he?
데리고 나가
Get him outta here.
다 떨어졌나?
Is it all off?
그런 것 같네요
I think so.
그래요, 새것 같아요
Yep, good as new.
자백하던가요?
Is he talking?
변호사라서 순순히 불더군요
He's a lawyer, so, yeah.
나탈리가 칼을 들이대고 위협해서
여기 왔다는데요 / 뭐라고요?
He says that you brought him
here at knifepoint. / What?
나탈리가 자길 스토킹했대요
미친 여자라고 그러더군요
He says that you've been stalking him
and that you're crazy.
무단 침입하셨잖아요
You were in his house.
- 이대로 놓아주면 안 돼요
- 지금으로서는
- You can't let him go.
- As of this moment,
이자를 어느 쪽이든 살인사건에
엮을 물적 증거가 없습니다
we have no physical evidence to connect
that man to either of the murders.
피자 상자는 어때요?
What about the pizza box?
글쎄요, 피자 상자를 찾는 경우
Well, if we could find the pizza box,
몽크의 집에서 나온 물건인데
and it came from Monk's house,
거기에 저자의 지문이 있는 거니
멋지게 사건이 해결되는 거죠
and it has his fingerprints on it,
well then, it's a slam dunk.
상자는 못 찾을 거예요
We're not gonna find it.
꿈 깨요, 관리자하고도
얘기해 봤는데
Forget it. I talked to the manager.
기록 같은 건 남기지 않는답니다
They don't keep any records.
어디든 갖다 버렸겠죠
They could've dumped it anywhere.
이 난장판을 보세요
I mean, look at this place.
이런 쓰레기 창고가 2개가 더 있고
바깥에는 더 많답니다 / 왜 그래?
There's two more warehouses,
and there's more outside. / What?
다들 조용
Shhh, everybody.
"폴리 울리 두들"이에요
Polly wolly doodle.
세상에, 줄리가 선물한 카드네요
음악 칩이 들어 있어요
Oh, my god, it's Julie's card.
It has a musical chip.
잠깐잠깐, 열어 보지 마
Wait, wait, wait.
Don't open it.
감식반을 기다려
Wait for forensics.
침대에서 나왔네요?
You got outta bed?
택시를 탔어요?
You took a taxi?
목욕 가운 바람으로요
In your bathrobe.
미치 말이 옳았어요
Mitch was right.
훌륭한 선수는 몸이
아파도 경기하죠
The great ones play hurt.
안녕하세요
Good morning.
집 앞에 나와 뭐하세요?
What are you doing outside
of your building?
그냥 앉아 있어요
I'm just sitting here.
바깥에요?
Outside?
오늘 날씨 정말 좋네요
It's a beautiful day.
몸도 괜찮아요, 많이 나아졌어요
I feel fine, much better.
잘 됐네요
Okay.
반장님께 얘기하고 오는 길이에요
So I just talked to the captain.
판사의 시신을 찾았어요
레지 데니슨이 모두 자백했어요
They found the judge's body.
Reggie Dennison confessed
to everything.
시신이 어디 있는지
직접 보여 주기도 했죠
He even showed them
where the body was.
진짜 뭣 때문에 나오신 거예요?
Really, what are you doing out here?
바깥은 싫어하잖아요
You hate outside.
제 성격이 좀 변했나 봐요
Maybe I've changed.
정말 진지하게 묻는 건데
뭣 때문에 나오신 거예요?
Seriously, what are you doing out here?
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)